Guide to the Burney Family Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Burney family collection
1767-1903
1790-1825
OSB MSS 3
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.05
(23 boxes)
The collection contains correspondence of several members of the Burney family, particularly Charles Burney (1726-1814); his children Charles Burney, D. D. (1757-1817), Fanny Burney (1752-1840), and Susanna Burney Philips; and Charles Burney IV (1815-1907). Other major correspondents include Alexandre d'Arblay, William Bewley, Peter Paul Dobree, George Isaac Huntingford, John Kaye, Hester Lynch Piozzi, Thomas Twining, and John Young.
Burney family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources.For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection spans the dates 1767-1903, but the bulk of the material dates from between 1790 and 1825.
The papers are arranged in several series. Series I, Burney Family Collection, is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and consists of the papers which had been previously cataloged in the card catalog. Major correspondents represented in the collection include Charles Burney (1726-1814), the musicologist and author of A General History of Music (1776); his son Charles Burney, D.D. (1757-1817); his daughter Fanny Burney d'Arblay, the diarist and author of Evelina (1778); and other members of the Burney family. Other correspondents include Alexandre d'Arblay, William Bewley, Hester Lynch Piozzi, Thomas Twining, and John Young.
Additions to the Burney Family Collection subsequent to June 1992 are listed in acquisition order in Series II, Burney Family Collection Additions, and Series III, Addition of August 2001.
The material in Series I has been described in Joyce Hemlow's A Catalogue of the Burney Family Correspondence, 1749-1878 (New York: New York Public Library, 1971). This work, it should be noted, is an index to holdings of Burney material at several institutions, including Yale University, and the New York Public Library. For further information, please contact the curator of the Osborn Collection.
Clergy -- England; Families -- England -- Domestic relations; Music -- Great Britain -- 18th century; Musicologists -- England -- Correspondence; Novelists, English -- 18th century; Women and literature -- Great Britain -- History -- 18th century; Women -- England; Great Britain -- History -- 1714-1837; London (England) -- Intellectual life; London (England) -- Social life and customs; Arblay, Alexandre Jean Baptiste Piochard, comte d', 1754-1818; Bewley, William, 1726-1783; Burney, Charles P. (Charles Parr), 1785-1864; Burney, Charles, 1726-1814; Burney, Charles, 1757-1817; Burney, Edward Francis, 1760-1848; Burney, Fanny, 1752-1840; Colman, George, 1732-1794; Dobree, Peter Paul, 1782-1825; Dyer, George; Finch, Robert, 1783-1830; Heber, Richard, 1773-1833; Huntingford, George Isaac, 1748-1832; Hüttner, Johann Christian, 1765-1849; Kaye, John, 1783-1853; Knight, Richard Payne, 1751-1824; Lansdowne, Henry Petty-Fitzmaurice, Marquess of, 1780-1863; Latrobe, Christian Ignatius, 1758-1836; Lawrence, Thomas, Sir, 1769-1830; Malone, Edmond, 1741-1812; Martini, Giovanni Battista, 1706-1784; Nichols, John, 1745-1826; Pacchierotti, Gasparo, 1740-1821; Parr, Samuel, 1747-1825; Piozzi, Hester Lynch, 1741-1821; Portland, William Henry Cavendish-Bentinck, Duke of, 1738-1809; Pretyman, George, 1750-1827; Scott, William, Baron Stowell of Stowell Park, 1745-1836; Southey, Robert, 1774-1843; Twining, Thomas, 1735-1804; Walker, Joseph C. (Joseph Cooper), -1810; Wilberforce, William, 1759-1833; Young, John, approximately 1750-1820; Burney family
- Burney Family Collection, Series I
  - ADKINS, THOMAS
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1903 Mar 30 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ADY, WILLIAM BRICE, 1816-1882
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1865 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AILESBURY, HENRIETTA MARIA (HILL) BRUDENELL-BRUCE
    Scope and Contents
    [MARCHIONESS OF, D. 1831]
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., [post 1806], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AINGER, ALFRED, 1837-1904
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1891 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ALEXANDER, J. D.
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1821 Sep 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALLEN, STEPHEN, 1755-1847
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1824, 1832-33 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ANONYMOUS
    - Obituary tribute to Charles Burney, D. D., 1818 JAN (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - ANSON, A.
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - AGUJARI, LUCREZIA, 1743-1783
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1775, 1776 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ARBLAY, ALEXANDER CHARLES LEWIS, D'
    - Letter to Mme d'Arblay, 1815 Jul 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1831 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ARBLAY, ALEXANDRE JEAN-BAPTISTE PIOCHARD
    [COMTE D', 1752-1818]
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1795 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1800 Jan 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letter to the editor of the Times, 1794 Mar 19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letter to the Princess Catherine C. polonoise, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Document to the Ministrie de la guerre, [1802 may 8] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Elegie: holograph poem, [post 1796] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Fragment: holograph poem, [post 1796] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Le Pardon: holograph poem, [post 1796] (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Les Riens: holograph poem, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - [Literary notes]: 5 holograph items, [1798] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - [Verses addressed to his wife]: holograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - ARBLAY, FRANCES (BURNEY) D', 1752-1840
    - Letter to Dorothea Gregory Alison, 1790 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letter to Jeremiah Bentham, 1790 Aug 26 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letter to Richard Bentley, 1835 Oct 16 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Verses and letter to Charles Burney, 1786 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1805 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1789-94 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1795 Jun-Jul (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1796-99 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [1800 Jan?] (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1800 Feb-Apr (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Letter to Charles and Rosette Burney, 1801 Apr 27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1801 Sep-Oct (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1802-03 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [1806 Aug] (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1812 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1813 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1814 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1815 Feb 22 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1815 Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1816 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1817 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, [1813?]-22 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1823-38 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Letter to Elizabeth Allen Burney (Mrs. C. Burney, Sr.), 1796 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Verses to Esther Burney (Mrs. C. P. Burney), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, [1783-85] (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1786-1800 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Letter to Mrs. Samuel Cooke, [ca. 1800] (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Letter to Mrs. Dickenson, 1785 Jul 17 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Letter to [Eve Maria (Violetti) Garrick], 1791 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Letter to [Sarah Martha Holroyd], [1816-18] (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Letters to John Jebb, 1830 Apr-Jul (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Letter draft to Longman & Co., [post 1824] (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Letter to Thomas Lowndes, 1813 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Letter to Elizabeth (Robinson) Montagu, 1785 Dec 20 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Letter to Thomas Payne, Jr., 1820 Apr 24 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Letters to Hester Lynch (Piozzi), [ca. 1782 Jun] (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Letter to [Princess Sophia], [1825] (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Letter to Mrs. Temple, 1835 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Letters to Mrs. G. Mary Ann (Post) Waddington, 1813, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Letter to unidentified recipient, [ca. 1793?] (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Articles of Agreement with Longman & Co. for publication of The Wanderer, 1813 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Letter to F. B. d'Arblay, 1817 Jun 10 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Copy of memorial inscription, [1840] (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Engraved portrait of Samuel Johnson, 1782 Feb 17 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "The petition of a fan to its mistress", 1788 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Portraits, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - ARCHER, CHARLES
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, [ca. 1890] (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - ARMSTRONG, JOHN
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - ASH, JOHN, 1723-1798
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., [1787?], 1790 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - ASHBURNHAM, GEORGE ASHBURNHAM, 1760-1830
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - ASPERNE, J.
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1818 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - AUGUSTA SOPHIA, PRINCESS, 1788-1840
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1824 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - AUSTIN, WILLIAM, 1721-1820
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1815 Mar 18 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - AYRTON, WILLIAM, 1777-1858
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1857 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - BACABER, HENRY HARVEY, 1775-1869
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1824 Jun 16 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - BACH, CARL PHILIPPE EMMANUEL, 1714-1788
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1776 Sep 5 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - BACON, JOHN, 1777-1859
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [1812?] Apr 24 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - BAILEY, JAMES, CA. 1790-1864
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, [post 1817] (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - BARNES, EDMUND LEWIN, 1752-1783
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1781 Feb-Aug (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - BANKS, DOROTHEA (WESTON-HUGESSEN), LADY, D. 1828
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1808 Dec 16 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - BANKS, JOHN CLEAVER, 1756-1845
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1802 Jun 21 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - BANKS, SIR JOSEPH, BART., 1743-1820
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1806 Aug 4 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1803, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - BARETTI, GIUSEPPE MARC ANTONIO, 1719-1789
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1772 Jun 24 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - BARING, ALEXANDER, 1ST BARON ASHBURTON, 1774-1848
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, [1821?] Nov 18 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - BARING, SIR FRANCIS, BART., 1740-1810
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1807 Apr 25 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - BARKER, EDMUND HENRY, 1788-1839
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1815, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1818-31 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - BARRETT, CHARLOTTE (FRANCES), 1786-1870
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1840 Jan 3 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - BARRETT, HENRY
    - Letters to the trustees of Mrs. Broome's marriage, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney and Martin C. Burney, 1840 Jan 3 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - BARRETT, RICHARD ARTHUR FRANCIS, 1812-1881
    - Letter to Charles Burney V, 1878 Apr 24 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - BARRINGTON, DAINES, 1727-1800
    - The Antiquity of the Violin: notes prepared for Charles Burney, Mus. D., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., [1774] Jul 19 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - BARRINGTON, SHUTE, BISHOP OF DURHAM, 1734-1826
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1792-1810 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - BARROW, SIR JOHN, 1764-1848
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1824 Jun 26 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - BARTLES, JOHN, CA. 1771-1823
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1816 Jun 26 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - BEATTIE, JAMES, 1735-1803
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1779 Apr 14 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - BEATTY, SIR WILLIAM, D. 1842
    - Letter to Miss Burney, 1832 Nov 16 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - BEAUMONT, SIR GEORGE HOWLAND, 1753-1827
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1802-14 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - BEGNY, J.
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1829 Jul 27 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - BELFOUR, JOHN
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1806 Nov 11 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - BELOE, WILLIAM, 1756-1817
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., [ca. 1787-ca. 1808] (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - BENSON, EDWARD WHITE, ARCHBISHOP OF CANTERBURY
    [1829-1896]
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1879, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - BENTINCK, LADY MARY (LOWTHER), LADY FREDERICK
    [Bentinck, d. 1862]
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1806-09, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - BERD, C. W.
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [pre-1791] (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - BERDMORE, SAMUEL, 1790-1802
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1790, [1792] (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - BERDMORE, SCROPE, CA. 1747-1812
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1808, 1809 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - BERESFORD-HOPE, ALEXANDER JAMES BERESFORD
    [1820-1887]
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1886 Jan 1 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - BERRY, MARY, 1763-1852
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1786, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - BEWLEY, WILLIAM, 1726-1783
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1757-64 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1764-70 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1771-74 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1775-77 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1778-79 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1780-82 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - BEXLEY, NICHOLAS VANSITTART, 1ST BARON, 1766-1851
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1818 Apr, May (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - BICKNELL, SABRINA (SIDNEY)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1787 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - BINDLEY, JAMES, 1737-1818
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1805 Sep 19 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - BLAGDEN, SIR CHARLES, 1748-1820
    - Letter to his brother, John., 1792 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - BLAGDEN-HALE, JOHN, D. 1814
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1808 Apr 28 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - BLOMFIELD, CHARLES JAMES, BISHOP OF LONDON
    [1786-1857]
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., [1807?]-17 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1818-50 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - BLORE, EDWARD, 1787-1879
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1829, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - BOISSONADE, JEAN-FRANCOIS, 1774-1857
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1802-[05?] (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - BOSWELL, JAMES, 1740-1795
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1792 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - BOURDOIS, ANNA MARIA (BURNEY), 1771-1856
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1806 Sep 2 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - Letter to her mother, Mrs. Charles Rousseau Burney, 1806 Sep 6 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - BOWDLER, FRANCES, MRS.
    - Letter to Frances Burney d'Arblay, 1817 Nov 28 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - BOWLES, JOHN
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1816 Jul 6 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - BOYD, ANDREW KENNEDY HUTCHISON, 1825-1860
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1881 Sep 6 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - BOYDELL, JOSIAH, 1752-1817
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1810 Nov 28 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - BOYLE-WELSINGHAM, CHARLOTTE (WILLIAMS), D. 1790
    - Letter to Frances (Burney) d'Arblay, 1785 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - BRADLEY, GEORGE GRANVILLE, 1821-1903
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1887 Mar 10 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - BRAYLEY, EDWARD WEDLAKE, 1772-1854
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., [1820 or later] (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1822 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - BREGUET, GABRIEL
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1816-17 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - BREQUIGNY, LOUIS-GEORGES OUDARD FEUDRIX DE
    [1714-1794]
    - Letter in Latin to Charles Burney (Box 2, Folder 140)
      - D.D., 1785 Jul 26
  - BRIGHT, WILLIAM, 1824-1901
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1888-91 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - BRISSOT DE WARVILLE, JACQUES PIERRE, 1754-1793
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1783 Mar, Jul (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - BRODIE, SIR BENJAMIN COLLINS, BART., 1783-1862
    - Letter to [Charles Parr Burney]., 1858 Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - BROOME, CHARLOTTE ANN (BURNEY) FRANCIS, 1761-1838
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1822-38 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Letters to Rosette (Rose) Burney, 1789-[1793?] (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Letter to Christian Latrobe, [pre-1786] Apr 13 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - BROOME, RALPH, SR., D. 1805
    - Portraits, etc., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - BROWNE, EDWARD HAROLD, BISHOP OF WINCHESTER
    [1811-1891]
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1873-77 (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - BRUCE, JAMES, 1730-1794
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1774 Oct 20 (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - BRUCE, MARY S.
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - BRYANT, JACOB, 1715-1804
    - Letters to Frances (Burney) D'Arblay, [Ca. 1786]-92 (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - BUCHAN, DAVID STEUART ERSKINE, 11TH EARL OF
    [1742-1829]
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1808, 12 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - BULL, RICHARD
    - Letter to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1784 Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - BUNTING, EDWARD, 1773-1843
    - Letters to Charles Burney, Mus. D., 1808 Aug, Dec (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - BURDETT-COUTTS, ANGELA GEORGINA, BARONESS
    [1814-1906]
    - Letter to Charles Burney IV, 1871 Jun 16 (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - BURGESS, THOMAS, BISHOP OF SALISBURY, 1756-1837
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1788-1804 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1818 Jan 9 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - BURNSIDE, ROBERT, 1758-1826
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1779-81 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - BUTE, JOHN STUART, 1ST MARQUIS OF, 1744-1814
    - Letter to Charles Burney, D.D., 1799 Dec 2 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - BUTLER, CHARLES, 1750-1832
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1799-1816 (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Letter to Charles Parr Burney, 1820 Aug 12 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - BUTLER, SAMUEL, BISHOP OF LICHFIELD, 1774-1839
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1807-13 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1822-24 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - BUTLER, WILLIAM JOHN, 1818-1894
    - Letters to Charles Burney IV, 1881-91 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - BURNEY, CHARLES, MUS. D., 1726-1814
    - Letter to Lord Bruce, 1798 Aug 23 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Letter to Lord Bruce, 1798 Sep 3 (Box 3, Folder 166)
    - Letter to Lord Bruce, Earl of Ailesbury, 1807 Aug 31 (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Letter to Lord Bruce, [ca. 1809 August] (Box 3, Folder 168)
    - Letter to Lady Bruce, [1806] Feb 6 (Box 3, Folder 169)
    - Letters to Lady Bruce, [1807-12?] (Box 3, Folder 170)
    - Letter to Lady Bruce, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 171)
    - Letter to Lord Charles [Brudenell- Bruce], [post 1798] (Box 3, Folder 172)
    - Letter to John Alcock, 1771 Nov 26 (Box 3, Folder 173)
    - Letter to Elizabeth (Allen) Allen Burney, [1764 Apr] (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, [1782]-85 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1786 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1787-90 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Letter to Frances Burney d'Arblay and Susanna, 1792 Apr 12 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1793-[96] (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1798-99 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1800-02 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1805-10, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Letters to Fanny Burney d'Arblay, 1812-13 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Letter to Benjamin Archer, 1779 Feb 2 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Letters to Samuel Arnold, 1797, [1802] (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Letter to Edmund Ayrton, 1803 Jan 14 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Letters to Lady Banks, 1808, 1812 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Letter to Mr. Baker, [1777?] Mar 17 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Letter to [Sir Joseph Banks], 1789 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Letters to Lady Banks, [post 1802]-10? (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Letter to Francois Barthelemon and his wife, 1789 Oct 21 (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Letters to John Belfour, [1806] (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - Letters to Lady Mary Lowther, [1802]-09 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Letter to Dr. William Bewley, 1776 Jan 30 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Letter to Henry Blencowe, 1783 Feb 23 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - Letters to Mrs. [Thomas] Blore, 1804 (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - Letter to the Rev. Chancellor Brand, [1807?] May 8 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - Letter draft to Mr. Broadwood and Mrs. Iremonger, 1812 Jun 29 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - Letters to the Earl of Buchan, ca. 1808 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - Letter draft to Richard Bull, [1784 post Nov 22] (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - Letter draft to Edmund Burke, 1788 Aug 4 (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - Letter draft to Edward Buntin, 1808 Sep 24 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1783-90 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - Letters to Charles Burney D.D., 1791-[98] (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1799 (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1800 Jan-May (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1801-03 (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1804 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1805-06 (Box 3, Folder 210)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1807 Jan-Mar (Box 3, Folder 211)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1808 (Box 3, Folder 212)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1809 (Box 3, Folder 213)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1810-11 (Box 3, Folder 214)
    - Letters to Charles Burney, D.D., 1812-13 (Box 3, Folder 215)
    - Letters to Charles Parr Burney, 1806-12 (Box 3, Folder 216)
    - Letter to Esther (Sleepe) Burney, [1752] (Box 3, Folder 217)
    - Letters to Rosette Burney, [1788]-99 (Box 3, Folder 218)
    - Letters to Rosette Burney, 1804 (Box 3, Folder 219)
    - Letters to Rosette Burney, 1805-07 (Box 3, Folder 220)
    - Letters to [John Wall Callcott], 1797-99 (Box 3, Folder 221)
    - Letters to John Wall Callcott, 1800-02 (Box 3, Folder 222)
    - Letters to John Wall Callcott, 1803 (Box 3, Folder 223)
    - Letters to Lord Cardigan, 1807-10, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Letter to Ralph Carr, 1791 Jul 13 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Letter to [Molly Carter], 1812 Jan 4 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Letter to John Courtenay, [post 1806] (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Letter to Mrs. Coway, 1788 Mar 2 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Letter to Richard Cox, [1791 Dec?] (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1792 Aug-Oct (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1792 Dec (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1793 Jan-Feb (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1793 Aug-Oct (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1794 (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1797-[98] (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1799 (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1801-03 (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1805-[post 1806] (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1807 (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, 1808 Feb-Nov (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - Letters to Frances Anne Crewe, [1809] (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - Letters to Samuel Crisp, 1770-71 (Box 4, Folder 242)